Ou Changkun

Curriculum Vitae

Science and art, life in between

@changkun 😯

changkun.de 😯

Munich, Germany

Feb. 2019 - Present

Munich, Germany

Apr. 2018 - Present

Munich, Germany Oct. 2016 - Jan. 2019

Chengdu, China

Chengdu, China

Huaihua, China

Changsha, China

Huaihua, China Sep.2006 - Jul.2009

Huaihua, China

Aug. 2016 - Sep. 2016

Sep. 2012 - Jul. 2016

Mar. 2010 - Jul. 2012

Aug. 2009 - Feb. 2010

Frauenlobstr. 7a

80337 Munich, Germany

**** +49 157 7214 1480 / +86 186 1322 5636

Born on October 25th 1993 in Zhijiang/Hunan/China

People's Republic of China citizenship

Single

Last update: July 25, 2019

Note: colored texts contains clickable URL.

Introduction

Changkun Ou is a research assistant at the University of Munich. His research topics are interdisciplinary in computational geometry, imitation learning, and human-computer interaction. In particular, he would like to leverage three-dimensional polygonal mesh representation learning and visual preference elicitation to develop efficient algorithms or industrial tools for 3D modeling and rendering.

Education

University of Munich (LMU)

Ph.D. Candidate in Media Informatics.

o Publications: Link

University of Munich

Master of Science in Computer Science; GPA: 2.05 in scale of 1.00 (best) to 4.0

University of Munich

Master of Science in Human-Computer Interaction (HCI); GPA: 1.63 in scale of 1.00 (best)

to 5.0, "qut".

• Thesis: Understanding and Predicting Web Browsing Behavior.

University of Electronic Science and Technology of China (UESTC)

Master of Engineering in Software Engineering

Southwest University for Nationalities (SWUN)

Bachelor of Engineering in Computer Science; Grade: 3.74 in scale of 4.00 (best) to 1.0, "Top

1 Student".

• Thesis: Designing Alternative Contact-free Control Modalities for Smart Watches.

First Middle School of Zhijiang

Senior Middle School; With university entrance examination (Gaokao)

Changsha Foreign Language School

Senior Middle School

Second Middle School of Zhijiang

Junior Middle School

Chengnan Primary School of Zhijiang

Primary School

Work Experiences

University of Munich

Research Assistant

• Teaching Assistant: Seminar Advances in Computer Graphics

• Tutor: Machine Learning, notes on GitHub.

o Tutor: Deep Learning and Artificial Intelligence, notes on GitHub

Page 1 of 4

Munich, Germany

Sep. 2000 - Jul. 2006

Aprl. 2018 - Present

LabEx Technology Ltd

Chengdu, China Apr. 2018 – Jan. 2019

• Team leader and leading backend development of the oversea product: I lead and responsible for the product development in backend and frontend. I evolve the existing architecture and split a monolithic backend web application into multiple microservices. The product scales machine cluster from 20 to 200 for active daily users, and its user group increases from 5k to 30k during my incumbency.

- Multi-cloud automation: I developed a fully automated multi-cloud resource management microservice in Go. The service defines a general abstraction cross all cloud provider, it automatically manages all user requested resources allocation and releases outdated resources. For instance, a user of the service can allocate new cloud instances for temporal using without noticing the instance was allocated in either AWS, AlibabaCloud, or others. The service supports more than 15 cloud products and integrated 3 cloud providers, being able to support almost unlimited concurrent users and has been used by 10k+ users.
- Cluster management service: I developed a microservice in Go that similar to Kubernetes and Docker Swarm. The service manages multiple server clusters, and auto-scaling its cluster size upon request cross multiple cloud providers. Each cluster contains multiple physical machines, and each machine runs many docker containers. The key feature of the service eliminates the difference between the physical machine and the docker container. The runtime of the service includes a system monitor with request prediction algorithm that I invented for efficient auto-scaling with consideration of overcommit ratio and a task scheduler for managing all distributed asynchronous task execution with two-level caching optimization.
- Remote desktop proxy: I developed a middleware that provides generic remote desktop proxy in Go and Cgo. The proxy translates VNC/RDP/SSH protocol data, and establish WebSocket connection to a web browser for providing remote desktop GUI.
- Used tech. stack: Vue, jQuery, Webpack, Electron; Backend: Go, Cgo, Gin, Beego, gRPC, MySQL, MongoDB, Redis, Hypervisor, Nginx, Docker, Kubernetes, AWS, AlibabaCloud, etc.

Fullstack Engineer (Freelance)

Munich, Germany

Rocketlingo UG

Nov. 2017 - Mar. 2018

- Language Teaching Voice Bot: I am part of the team in developing a voice bot that provides English learning teaching service. The bot can communicate with its user and improve their English skill by the real-time response. My responsibility is to implement the backend support designed conversations using Amazon Alexa.
- Speech Recognition Solution & Web Development: I responsible for the development of speech recognition solution over web technologies, such as using WebSocket for audio streaming, using Google Cloud STT and TTS services for speech recognition and synthesis, etc. The challenging part of using existing speech recognition service for a language learning application is a new language learner sometimes does not produces positive audio samples, and even multilingual. Therefore, I developed many text-based falt tolerances technique for improving the understanding of user speech based on machine learning algorithms.
- Used Tech. Stack: Frontend: Angular, Backend: NodeJS, ExpressJS, WebSocket, Python, Flask, MongoDB, Elasticsearch, AWS Serverless, Tensorflow, Numpy, Matplotlib

Shiyanlou Software Engineer (Intern)

Academic Tutor

Chengdu, China
Jun. 2016 - Sep. 2016

o Recommendation System: Online course recommendation system; Python; MongoDB; Collaborate Filtering

- o Distributed Log System: Elasticsearch; Logstash; Kibana; Redis
- o Cross Platform Desktop Client: Electron based development for macOS/Windows/Linux
- Teaching Meterial Writing: Modern C++ based teaching meterial writing

SWUN Lecture "Human-Computer Interaction"

Chengdu, China

Jul. 2015

Skills

- I have good skills in web development and machine learning. and I can use the following languages: **go**; **python**; **javascript**; **c/c++** (**for optimization**); markdown; IATEX; native Chinese; fluent professional English; elementary German
- Certificates: Coursera, Andrew Ng: Deep Learning Specializations, certificates: 1, 2, 3, 4, 5

Open Source Contribution

- Tensorflow (130k+ stars): Contributor
- Go (60.1k+ stars): Contributor
- etcd (26.1k+ stars): Contributor
- Modern C++ Tutorial (3.9k+ stars): I am the author of the book. The book provides the state-of-the-art content towards modern C++, which includes C++11/14/17/20.
- Go under the hood (800+ stars): I am the author of the book. The book discusses Go source code, includes its runtime scheduler, garbage collection, compiler and etc.
- Official Tensorflow document translation (3.5k+ stars): I am the main contributor and project maintainer.
- Juejin Translation Public Community (22.6k+ stars): Major contributor, translated 50+ articles. Main reviewer of AI related articles.
- occamy: The project implements a modern remote desktop proxy written in Go. It provides web browser GUI for connecting vnc/rdp/ssh servers.
- gomat: The package provides cache-aware lock-free tiling optimization matrix utilities in Go.
- sched: The package for a high performance reliable task scheduling in Go.
- Check my GitHub homepage for more projects: github.com/changkun

Open Source Contribution

- Tensorflow (130k+ stars): Contributor
- Go (60.1k+ stars): Contributor
- etcd (26.1k+ stars): Contributor
- Modern C++ Tutorial (3.9k+ stars): I am the author of the book. The book provides the state-of-the-art content towards modern C++, which includes C++11/14/17/20.
- Go under the hood (800+ stars): I am the author of the book. The book discusses Go source code, includes its runtime scheduler, garbage collection, compiler and etc.
- Official Tensorflow document translation (3.5k+ stars): I am the main contributor and project maintainer.
- Juejin Translation Public Community (22.6k+ stars): Major contributor, translated 50+ articles. Main reviewer of AI related articles.
- occamy: The project implements a modern remote desktop proxy written in Go. It provides web browser GUI for connecting vnc/rdp/ssh servers.
- gomat: The package provides cache-aware lock-free tiling optimization matrix utilities in Go.
- sched: The package for a high performance reliable task scheduling in Go.
- Check my GitHub homepage for more projects: github.com/changkun

Public Activities

•	Presenter at The ACM CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems	Glasgow, UK May. 2019
•	Student Volunteer at Conference Smart Graphics 2015	Chengdu, China <i>Aug. 2015</i>
•	Guigu Lab Team Leader at SWUN	Chengdu, China Sep. 2014 – Jun. 2015
•	Mathematical Modeling Association Academic Vice Director $at\ SWUN$	Chengdu, China Oct. 2012 – Jun. 2014

Honors & Awards

•	Siemens AILab Hackathon 2nd Winner	Munich, Germany Nov. 2017
•	China National Scholarship at UESTC	Chengdu, China Sep. 2016
•	Excellent Bachelor Graduation Thesis Award $at SWUN$	Chengdu, China Jun. 2016
•	Best University Graduates Student Award at Sichuan Province	Chengdu, China Jan. 2016
•	Outstanding Student Scholarship at SWUN	Chengdu, China Nov. 2015
•	Student Innovative Annual Excellent Project at SWUN	Chengdu, China Jun. 2015
•	Sichuan Province Computer Production Competition 2nd Award	Chengdu, China May 2015
•	China National Scholarship at SWUN	Chengdu, China Sep. 2014
•	American Mathematical Contest in Modeling(MCM) 2014 $Meritorious \ Winner$	Chengdu, China <i>Apr. 2014</i>

Personal Interests

- Open source contributions: Writting open source book; Contributing and maintaining open source softwares
- Video blogging: Making videos on YouTube channel
- Blogging and knowledge sharing: on https://changkun.de
- Video gaming: Sony Playstation and Nintendo Switch player

References

- Prof. Andreas Butz: currently supervise for Master studies at LMU Munich Medieninformatik, Munich, Germany
- Prof. Heinrich Hußmann: exchange student course "Human-Computer Interaction I" at Southwest University for Nationalities, Chengdu, China
- Dr. Daniel Buschek: currently supervise for Master thesis at LMU Munich Medieninformatik, Munich, Germany
- Malin Eiband: currently supervise for Master thesis at LMU Munich Medieninformatik, Munich, Germany
- Florian Lachner: supervised for individual practical course at LMU Munich Medieninformatik, Munich, Germany
- Prof. Yaxi Chen: supervised for bachelor thesis at Southwest University for Nationalities, Chengdu, China
- Prof. Wei Zhou: supervised for bachelor thesis at Southwest University for Nationalities, Chengdu, China